# Md Farid Uddin

## Full Stack Software Engineer







github.com/kironiitdu

I'm a software engineer specialized in building Web Applications. I love building Web Application using .NET technologies. As for the backend, I work with ASP.NET Core Web API & SQL in frontend I prefer JavaScript base framework following suitable architectural pattern and principles. I have extensive experience on Azure as well. I'm a team player who is passionate about helping and collaborating within the team to make the businesses succeed.

#### **Relevant Experience**

#### Full Stack Software Engineer @Wicresoft-Microsoft

December 2018 - Present, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China

- Write modern, performant, robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Working with .Net base platforms, frameworks, and Cognitive service. Developing web base application for Microsoft support service base eco-system.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, SQA team, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.

#### Software Engineer .NET @Prime Tech Solution

January 2015 - December 2018, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developed and maintained code for in-house enterprise supply chain management eco-system.
- Manually tested different features, fixed bug and developed new features requirements
- ▶ Ship Engine, Shopify, UPS API Integration, New Web Hook Development.

### **Professional Certification**

Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (Since 2015)

- ⊳ C#, Asp.net MVC, Entity Framework, LINQ
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.

Azure Web Service (Since 2015)

- Azure Web App, Azure Active Directory
- Azure Function, Microsoft graph

IT Engineers Certificate Exam (Since 2017)

- Bangladesh Computer Council
- ▶ Issued By BJIT, Japan

#### **Project Experience**

#### **Microsoft Partner Center API**

- ▶ Partner Center streamlines several business processes to make it easier for Microsoft partners to manage their relationship with Microsoft and their customers. Partner Center gives access to the tool helps Microsoft Partner to get work done.
- Technology Used- C#, Asp.net core MVC, Asp.net Web API, Entity Framework 5, Azure Active Directory, Azure SQL, React.

- ▶ An AI based virtual co-working solution which helps Microsoft customer regarding various technical issue which already been resolved. Using Azure Cognitive Service filter customer query and analysis text sentinels and finally execute result if the issue is customer having already has solution which save customers time and support service charge.
- Technology Used- C#, Azure Bot Framework, Microsoft Graph, LUIS, QNA maker, Azure Function.

#### **Advance Pro Inventory Management**

- > AdvancePro is a complete and highly adaptable inventory management solution consist of inventory management functionality with multi-platform including desktop, web and mobile which can synchronize order among Shopify, WooCommerce and any other API base inventory
- Technology Used- C#, Asp.net MVC, Web API, Kendo UI, Ado.Net, SQL Server 2014, Crystal Report.

#### **Skills**

#### **Programming**

C#, ASP.NET Core, Web API, Dot Net 5-6, Entity Framework All version, Data structure and call stack mechanism, Object Oriented Programming, Code Refactoring, Asynchronous request handling, Thread management, Locking mechanism.

#### **Database**

Data Modeling and Normalization using 3NF Entity relationship diagram (ERD) T-SQL Any Level of Complexity Complex Store Procedures or Trigger Transaction control with full ACID Manage Transaction Isolation Level and database concurrency

#### Front End

Kendo UI, jQuery, JavaScript

#### **Tools & Platforms**

GitHub, Azure DevOps, Draw.IO.

#### **Achievements**

Best Performance Awards 4th times 450+ Problem solved on stack overflow 10K Reputation

#### Education

#### University of Dhaka

2016-2017//Bangladesh

Master's in information technology **CGPA 3.50** 

#### Jagannath University

2014-2015//Bangladesh

Diploma in Software Architecture & Design.

**CGPA 3.75** 

#### Jagannath University

2008 - 2013 //Bangladesh

Bachelor of Arts.

**CGPA 3.58**